Marco Scigliuzzo, MSc

marco.scigliuzzo.physics@gmail.com

(S) +39 3487098121 (S) marco.scigliuzzo.physics

https://github.com/sciglio

nttps://scholar.google.com/citations?user=2CxeAREAAAAJ

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/marco-scigliuzzo-033b8588/

I am a physicist interested in quantum optics, with experience in superconducting circuits, from design to fabrication, measurements and data analysis. My work focuses on the effects of classical and quantum environments on mechanical and electrical quantum system.



Education

2016 – now Graduate Student, Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden. Supervisor: Per Delsing Thesis preliminary title: Effects of the environment on quantum systems.

2010 – 2016 M.Sc. Physics, University of Salento, Italy. 110/110 Laude. Supervisor: Giuseppe Maruccio Thesis: Optimization of SAW filters and resonators of doi:10.13140/RG.2.2.27702.19521.

2006 – 2010 **ISUFI License**, University of Salento, Italy. 100/100. Supervisor: Dario Pisignano Thesis: Realization and modeling of aqueous electrospun microjets (in Italian)

2006 – 2009 **B.Sc. Physics**, *University of Salento*, Italy. 110/110 Laude. Supervisor: Luigi Martina Thesis: *Vortexes in quantum fluids* (in Italian)

Competences

Prototyping and Simulation

Microwave Parametric electrostatic and electromagnetic simulation for circuits and sample holders design (electrodes capacitance, capacitive coupling, box and chips modes)

Comsol Multiphysics, SONNET®

Acoustic Quasistatic electro-mechanic simulation for surface and bulk acoustic wave generation

by superconducting circuit in the GHz range

Thermal Thermalization dynamics and thermal gradient in cryogenic environment

CAD Lithography circuits patterns, sample holder and cryo-parts 3D design Autocad, Solidworks

Fabrication

Lithography Fabrication of superconducting circuits based on Josephson Junctions with Lift Off and wet etching. Optical and Electron Beam Lithography, Electron beam metal deposition

and Manhattan procedure Josephson Junction.

Metrology Standard characterization instrument: Scanning Electron microscopy (SEM), Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM), Optical Microscope, Profilometers.

Chip Wafer cliving or dicing machine (for GaAs or Si). Aluminium ultrasound bonder.

Cryogenic and Microwave Equipment

Set-up Coherent and pulsed **microwave resonators and qubits** setup: Vector Network Analyzer (VNA), up-down conversion board, arbitrary waveform (AWG) and Analog to digital converter (ADC), DC source for superconducting coil.

Software: Labber

Competences (continued)

Protocols Single and multi-qubits characterization and control.

Cryogenic Operation, custom modification and maintenance of Dilution refrigerator (BF LD250).

Data Analysis and Programming

Analysis **Theory** Derive Hamiltonian and solve the dynamics for small scale superconducting circuits, including experimental non-idealities or fabrication scattering. Data Process Model adaptation to measured data, device parameter extraction

Software: Mathematica, Python, Matlab

Languages

Python Proficient Instruments drivers, Data analysis and visualization. Elementary knowledge of quantum oriented libraries: ******QuTip, **SCQubits ≥**, **Qiskit** Metal C and C++ Intermediate Micro controller programming and solving simple algebraic or differential equations with parallel processing (MPI library)

Unix Bash *Intermediate* Scripts for file processing and computer maintenance.

HTML Elementary Basic syntax with little knowledge of CSS.

Visual and written production

InkScape *Intermediate* Scientific drawing of info-grafic **Images**

Gimp Elementary Basic command for image manipulation

Blender Elementary Short animations for didactic purpose and video editing. Videos

Text LITEX Proficient Focus on scientific text (research articles)

Research Publications and Conference Talk

Publication Metrics: Citations 99, H-index 3, i10-Index 2 (retrieved from Google Scholar on August 10, 2021) **Journal Articles**

- Osman, A., Simon, J., Bengtsson, A., Kosen, S., Krantz, P., Lozano, D., ... Fadavi Roudsari, A. (2021). Simplified josephson-junction fabrication process for reproducibly high-performance superconducting qubits. Applied Physics Letters, 118(6), 064002. Publisher: American Institute of Physics. **𝚱** doi:10.1063/5.0037093
- Andersson, G., Bilobran, A. L. O., Scigliuzzo, M., de Lima, M. M., Cole, J. H., & Delsing, P. (2021). Acoustic spectral hole-burning in a two-level system ensemble. npj Quantum Information, 7(1), 1-5. Number: 1 Publisher: Nature Publishing Group. @doi:10.1038/s41534-020-00348-0
- Scigliuzzo, M., Bengtsson, A., Besse, J.-C., Wallraff, A., Delsing, P., & Gasparinetti, S. (2020). Primary thermometry of propagating microwaves in the quantum regime. Physical Review X, 10(4), 041054. Publisher: American Physical Society. @doi:10.1103/PhysRevX.10.041054
- Scigliuzzo, M., Bruhat, L. E., Bengtsson, A., Burnett, J. J., Roudsari, A. F., & Delsing, P. (2020). Phononic loss in superconducting resonators on piezoelectric substrates. New Journal of Physics, 22(5), 053027. Publisher: IOP Publishing. 6 doi:10.1088/1367-2630/ab8044
- Burnett, J. J., Bengtsson, A., Scigliuzzo, M., Niepce, D., Kudra, M., Delsing, P., & Bylander, J. (2019). Decoherence benchmarking of superconducting qubits. npj Quantum Information, 5(1), 1–8. Number: 1 Publisher: Nature Publishing Group. @doi:10.1038/s41534-019-0168-5
- Maruccio, C., Scigliuzzo, M., Rizzato, S., Scarlino, P., Quaranta, G., Chiriaco, M. S., ... Maruccio, G. (2019). Frequency and time domain analysis of surface acoustic wave propagation on a piezoelectric gallium arsenide substrate: A computational insight. Journal of Intelligent Material Systems and Structures, 30(6), 801-812. Publisher: SAGE Publications Ltd STM. @ doi:10.1177/1045389X18803461

Rizzato, S., **Scigliuzzo**, **M.**, Chiriacò, M. S., Scarlino, P., Monteduro, A. G., Maruccio, C., ... Maruccio, G. (2017). Excitation and time resolved spectroscopy of SAW harmonics up to GHz regime in photolithographed GaAs devices. *Journal of Micromechanics and Microengineering*, 27(12), 125002. Publisher: IOP Publishing. 6 doi:10.1088/1361-6439/aa8186

Submitted for publication

Andersson, G., Jolin, S. W., **Scigliuzzo**, **M.**, Borgani, R., Tholén, M. O., Haviland, D. B., & Delsing, P. (2020, July 11). Squeezing and correlations of multiple modes in a parametric acoustic cavity. arXiv: 2007.05826. Retrieved from 6 http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.05826

Contributed Talks

- Scigliuzzo, M., Calajò, G., Ciccarello, F., Lozano, D., Bengtsson, A., Scarlino, P., ... Gasparinetti, S. (2021). Probing nonlinear photon scattering with artificial atoms coupled to a slow-light waveguide. APS march meeting. Retrieved from ## https://meetings.aps.org/Meeting/MAR21/Session/P28.8
- Scigliuzzo, M., Bruhat, L. E., Bengtsson, A., Burnett, J. J., Roudsari, A. F., & Delsing, P. (2019). Phononic losses in superconducting coplanar waveguide resonators on piezoelectric substrates. APS march meeting. Retrieved from 6 https://meetings.aps.org/Meeting/MAR19/Session/K26.14

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant

Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden.

PhD program: Hands-on Quantum Technology (2019-2020)

Laboratory Sessions measuring dechoerence of qubit and reports Correction

Master Program: Quantum Optics and Quantum Informatics (2017-2020)

Tutotial Classes, Laboratory Sessions, Hand-ins Correction

Master Program: Superconductivity and Low Temperature Physics (2016-

2019)

Hand-ins and Exams Correction. High- T_c SQUID lab session

Bachelor Program: Physics and chemistry for civil engineers (2017-2019)

Elementary thermodynamics Tutorial Classes and exercise correction

Master Program: Modeling and fabrication of micro/nanodevices (2017-2018)

Cleanroom tutorial for small groups

Student Supervision

Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden.
Master student Supervision: Vukan Levajac, Measuring Coherence of a Coaxmon (now @ TU Delft - QuTech)

Award and Scholarship

Research and Innovation Award. *University of Salento*. Best Master Thesis of the year.

LLP/Erasmus Scholarship. *University of Salento*. 5 months placement program in Oxford University, United Kingdom.

2011-2013 Full Scholarship, 2 years, *University of Salento*. Master study in university institute ISUFI.

Full Scholarship, 3 years, *University of Salento*. Undergraduate study in university institute ISUFI (national selection).

Ranked in 4^{th} place for 5 years Scholarship Italian Physics Society, national selection. (declined because not compatible with college scholarship)

Languages

Italian Mother-tongue

English Proficient. Written and oral production with scientific focus.

Elementary. Limited understanding and small vocabulary.

Elementary. Limited understanding and small vocabulary.

References

Per Delsing

Professor

Chalmers University,

Kemivägen 9, 412 58 Göteborg

per.delsing@chalmers.se

Pasquale Scarlino

Assistant Professor

EPFL,

PH D₃ 495 (Bâtiment PH) Lausanne

pasquale.scarlino@epfl.ch

Simone Gasparinetti

Assistant Professor

Chalmers University,

Kemivägen 9, 412 58 Göteborg

✓ simoneg@chalmers.se

Giuseppe Maruccio

Associate Professor

University of Salento,

Via per Arnesano, 73100 Lecce

giuseppe.maruccio@unisalento.it